A Guide to the Department of Conservation and Development, Division of History, Records, 1927-1950
Library of Virginia
- Series I. Correspondence, 1927-1950 (Accession 24806a)
  - Subseries A: Correspondence, 1927-1950
    - Topics
      - Game and Inland Fisheries, Commission of (pamphlet) (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Genealogy and History (publications) (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - General Assembly (Bills, etc.0 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Gettysburg Campaign (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Governor's Mansion - Notes on (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Governors of Virginia (Colony and State) (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Guide to HIstorical Points and other Places in Virginia (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Guns (French) Landed at South Quay (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence
      - Hackley, W.E. - Hall, Wilmer L. (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Haller, Ellis M. - Hanson, Jospeh Mills (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Harbough, Sally - Harris, H.B. (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Harris, J.N. - Hart, V. Stanley (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Hartman, Elizabeth - Haw, Nannie B. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Hawes, E.M. - Headman, Mrs. Mary Hoss (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Heath, Mrs. Benjamin Dawson - Henry, Mrs. W. Wirt (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Henshaw, Mrs. Conrad - Higgenbotham, Mrs. E.G. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Higgins, Mrs. Clayton - Hite, Maude C. (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Hoadley, E. - Holladay, Waller (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Holland, Dr. C.G. - Hope, Jr., William F. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Hopkins, Arthur E. - Horton, H.M. (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Hosier, J. Walter - Hudgins, Alexander (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Hudnall, Mrs. Edna - Hunter, W.P. (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Hunton, Jr., Eppa - Hylton, Howard (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Additional Correspondence
      - Hall, Wilbur C. (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Hall, Wilmer L. (State Librarian) (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Handy, Mrs. Fred A.G., Alexandria, VA (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Happel, Ralph (National Park Service) (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Harrington, Dr. J.C. (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Harrison, Travis C. (Files on Olive Branch Christian Church, Brunswick County, Marker Requests) (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Hart, Capt. R.W.B. (Lynchburg City Manager) (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Hayes, Rutherford B. (Personal - Dr. Eckenrode) (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Headland, Frank (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Henderson, Dr. Archibald (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Hiden, Mrs. P.W., Newport News, VA (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Hill, D.H. (clippings) (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Hobart, Inc., W.F. (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Hodgkin, Dr. William H. (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - Hood, Samuel Stevens (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - Hosterman, A.D., Chairman, Ohio Revolutionary Memorial Commission, Springfield, Ohio (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - Hudson, Captain Christopher (Box 23, Folder 15)
      - Hughes, Robert M., Norfolk, VA (Box 23, Folder 16)
      - Hummel, Edward A., Supt., Fredericksburg, VA (Box 23, Folder 17)
      - Hutton, H.I., Warrenton, VA (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Topics
      - Highways - Virginia (Box 23, Folder 19)
      - Historical Highway Markers - Letters (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Historical Highway Markers - Letters (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Historical Highway Markers - Letters (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Historical Survey Project (WPA) - Miscellaneous Material (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Hotels - Rates, etc. (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - House of Delegates (Speakers) (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence
      - I.V.N.A. - Ivy, Elizabeth (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Additional Correspondence
      - Ickes, Harold L. (Dept. of Interior) (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Topics
      - Inquiriers Regarding Markers (List) (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Institutions, Educational (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Insurance Forms (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - Investigation of Marker System (Copies of Letters) - See folder under Marker System Investigation (Out of State Letters)
      - Invitations and Programs (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - Invoices and Shipping Notices (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence
      - Jabour, Mrs. Sam - Janney, Nancy Lee (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - Jaquith, Mrs. Sommer B. - Jervey, Mrs. William Palmer (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - Jesse, Mrs. James D. - Johnson, Louise (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Johnson, M.R. - Johnstone, Mrs. H.I. (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Joines, James E.A. - Jones, Polly (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Jones, R.L. - Juergens, William J. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Additional Correspondence
      - James, Mrs. E. Stewart (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Johns, Jay W. (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Johnson, A.S. (V.P. & G.M., James River Bridge Corp., Smithfield, VA) (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Johnson, R.P. (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Johnston, J. Ambler (Secretary, Richmond Battlefield Corp.) (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Jones, Chapin (State Forester) (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Topics
      - Jackson, "Stonewall" - The Last Days of Stonewall Jackson (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Jackson Monument at Manassas (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - The Jackson Trail (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - James River and Kanawha Canal (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Jamestown Pageant (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Jamestown, Settlement of (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Jefferson Memorial at Washington (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - Jewish Army and People (Magazine "Answer") (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence
      - Kahn, Herman - Keely, Maud McLure (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - Keen, Mrs. Barton L. - Kemper, W.M. (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - Kendall, A.W. - Kerr, W.R. (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - Kessler, C.L. - Kimbel, Ken (Box 26, Folder 12)
      - Kimmell, J.W. - Kiracofe, J.W. (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Kirk, Annie B. - Kocher, A. Lawrence (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Koen, E.B. - Kyle, Mrs. Julia S. (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Additional Correspondence
      - Keiley, W.S., New York ("The Batter's Last Shot" - Story) (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Keim, George deB., Edgewater, NJ (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Keister, E.E. (Manager, Shenandoah Publishing House) (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - Kemper, Charles E., State Hospital, Staunton, VA (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Kemper, Colonel W.M. (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Kern, Mrs. G.T.W. ("History of Virginia") (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - Ketron, P.E. (Director of Purchasing Division) (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - King, George H.S. (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Krock, Arthur (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Krug, J.A. (Secretary, Board of Geographic Names) (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence
      - Labaree, Leonard W. - Lambert, Darwin S. (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Lambert, Mrs. Fauntleroy - Langston, Myrtle (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Lankford, Jr., Charles M. - Layman, Kate (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Lea, James A. - Lee, Mrs. Tom (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Lee, W.C. - Lewis, Ben (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Lewis, Mrs. C.E. - Lilly, Kate (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Limerick Co., J. Arthur - Littlejohn, Margaret (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Littleton, Frank C. - Love, S.B. (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Loveman, Amy - Lyon, Robert Dorsey (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Additional Correspondence
      - Landers, Colonel H.L., Washington, DC (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Leland, Dr. Waldo G. (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - Letcher, Captain Greenlee D. (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - Lichford, L.E. (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - Long, Lee, Dante, VA (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - Lyne, Cassie Moncure (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Topics
      - Lafayette and Cornwallis in Virginia, 1781 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Lee, Robert E. (History by Douglas Southall Freeman) (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Libraria (Virginia Public Libraries) (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - List of Battlefield Markers in Richmond Vicinity - See Richmond Battlefield Markers (Richmond Defense) for list of inscriptions
      - Lisst of Civil War Houses Standing to Date (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - List of States of Union and their Capitals (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Longstreet, Life of General (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence
      - Mabry, Mrs. J. Hughes - Mahoney, Mrs. M.P. (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Maier, R.W.R. - Mann, Vear (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Manning, Mrs. Mary C. - Marr, Janey Barron Hope (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Marsh, S.H. - Mason, Minnie L. (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - Mason, Jr., Mrs. S. Blount - Maxey, Rad (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - May, George E. - McCann, Bernard (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - McCarter, William H. - McDermott, F.J. (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - McDevitt, Mrs. Harry S. - McIntyre, R.A. (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - McKee, Frank - Meek, J.T. (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - Megee, Dorothy - Middough, Lorne (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - Milbourne, Mrs. V.S. - Miller, Hunter (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - Miller, J.G. - Miner, R.C. (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Minge, John H. - Monnette, Orra E. (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Monroe, F. - Moore, Esther (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Moore, F.W. - Morgan, Geoffrey (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Morgan, Georgia - Morton, R.L. (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Morton, Mrs. Susan R. - Moxey, Cosby (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - Mugler, Mrs. Charles W.J. - Musgrave, Philip Cebern (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Mussaeus, Allen - Myers, William Stair (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Additional Correspondence
      - MacClenney, W.E., Suffolk, VA (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - McCandish, W.T. (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - McClevy, W.W. (Director of Purchasing Division) (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - McConnell, Dr. J.P., East Radford, VA (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - McCorkle, Dr. Emmett (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - McGill, William M., Charlottesville, VA (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - Tracy W. McGregor Library, Charlottesville, VA (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - McMillen, Wheeler (Editor of Farm Journal) (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - McWane, Fred E. (Director, Virginia Capital Bicentennial Commission) (Box 33, Folder 11)
      - Moon, William A. (Historical Inventory) (Box 33, Folder 12)
      - Moomaw, B.F. (Roanoke Chamber of Commerce) (Box 33, Folder 13)
      - Moore, R. Walton (Box 33, Folder 14)
      - Morton, Paul (Box 33, Folder 15)
      - Moulsdale, Miss Sidney K., University, VA (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Topics
      - Mailing List (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - Manassas Battlefield Park (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - Maps - See Also Oversize Map Case 24, Drawer 10 (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - Mariners' Museum (Huntington), Newport News, VA (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - McClellan Biography (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - Military Information (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - Monroe Doctrine (pamphlet) (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - Monthly Reports, January 1948-March 1950 (Box 34, Folder 9)
      - "Mother of States" Monument (Box 34, Folder 10)
      - Motor Vehicles, Division of (Box 34, Folder 11)
      - Mottoes (all kinds) (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence
      - Nash, Mrs. F.M. - Newbill, Willard D. (Box 34, Folder 13)
      - Newell, A.C. - New York World Telegram (Box 34, Folder 14)
      - Nicholas, Mrs. George - Norris, Jr., R.O. (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Norris, W.W. - Nye, Gerald P. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Additional Correspondence
      - Naylor, Hugh E. (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Nelson, R.F. (Director of Publicity, Richmond Chamber of Commerce) (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Topics
      - National Anthem (Star Spangled Banner) (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - National Park Service, Mosque, Richmond, VA (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - National Parks Association (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Natural Wonders, Amusement Centers, Parks and Forests (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - New York Worlds's Fair (Exhibits) (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - Nickname of Virginia (Commonwealth of Virginia) (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Norfolk and Western Railroad Company (Menu Cards) - (Fred Stone) - See Also Oversize Map Case 24, Drawer 10 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence
      - Oast, Edward L. - Oldfield, James A. (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - Oldham, M.C. - Overbey, Jean S. (Box 35, Folder 13)
      - Overhulse, Jesse William - Ozlin, Thomas W. (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Topics
      - Old Homes and Churches by County (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - Old Letters (copies) (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - Ordnance (2 cannon and 12 balls), Meade Post No. 1, G.A.R. of Pennsylvania (for new battlefield marker) (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - Office Equipment (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence
      - Pace, H.M. - Palmer, John McAuley (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Palmer, Vera - Parmenter, Joseph G. (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - Parr, Clyde - Patton, R.S. (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Paul, John - Pearson, James Larkin (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Pearson, Milo L. - Perry, William G. (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Peters, David W. - Pierrepont, Mrs. Alice V.D. (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Pierson, Lucy Lelia - Pollock, Mrs. John G. (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Poole, Mrs. G.D. - Powell, S.P. (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Powell, William S. - Price, H.L. (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Price, Mrs. James H. - G.P. Putnam's Sons (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Additional Correspondence
      - Page, Elizabeth (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - Pederson, Fred C. (State Forester) (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Peebles, Anne Bradbury, Washington, DC (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - Peed, Garland Powell, New York City (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - Peery, Governor George C. (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Peirce, Mrs. C.T., Nuttsville, VA (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Peterson, Charles E., Washington, DC (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Phelps, Mrs. C.W., Burkeville, VA (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Pike, Albert, Washington, DC (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Pleasants, M.F. (1945-1949) (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Pollard, Governor John Garland (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - Pretlow, Mary D. (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - Price, Governor James H. (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Topics
      - Pageant at Virginia Beach, 1938 ("The Turbulent Deep" by T. Beverly Campbell) (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Pamphlets on Virginia (Miscellaneous) (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Pay Roll Deduction Plan (Bonds and Old Age Retirement) (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Petersburg Battlefields (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Police Lectures (Capt. C.W. Woodson, Jr.) (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - Poll Tax (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Programs (Miscellaneous) (Box 39, Folder 7)
      - Public Records of Virginia (Virginia State Library) (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - Purchasing Division, Director of (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence
      - Quarles, H.S. - Quinn, I.T. (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Topics
      - Questionnaire - Position Description (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence
      - Raab, Henry S. - Randolph, Robert I. (Box 39, Folder 12)
      - Rankin, Daniel S. - Reed, Muriel (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - Reed, P.L. - Reynolds, Hewitt (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Rhinelander, Philip - Richman, Luther A. (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - Richmond Army Services Forces Depot - Rives, Mrs. John D. (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - Roan, James Tate - Robertson, Katherine (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - Robertson, R.A. - Rooke, J. Roland (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - Rorer, Henry S. - Rowe, Virginia Rives (Box 40, Folder 6)
      - Rowell, Mrs. Charles E. - Rush, John A. (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Russell, A.N. - Ryland, Elizabeth H. (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Additional Correspondence
      - Rawley, Heath J. (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Richardson, Mrs. Eudora Ramsey (WPA - Writers Guide Project) (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Roberts, Rufus, Culpeper, VA (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Roineete, Lloyd M. (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - Robinson, Jr., W.M., Yorktown, VA (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - Rust, Senator John W., Fairfax, VA (Box 41, Folder 8)
      - Ryland, Dr. Garnett (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Topics
      - Railroads (Box 41, Folder 10)
      - Reorganization of the Dept. of Conservation and Development, 12-29-1948 (Duke's Final Report) (Box 41, Folder 11)
      - Requisitions (pipe, etc.) (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Richmond Battlefield Markers (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Richmond Battlefield Park (1941 Inspection Reports) (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - Richmond Battlefield Park (Aerial Views of Fields) (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Richmond Battlefield Park (Booklets) (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - Richmond Battlefield Park (Cold Harbor Area) (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - Richmond Battlefield Park (Fort Harrison Area) - See Also Oversize Box 1, Folder 1 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - Richmond Battlefield Park (General File) (part one) - See Also Oversize Box 1, Folder 2 (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - Richmond Battlefield Park (General File) (part two) - See Also Oversize Box 1, Folder 2 (Box 42, Folder 9)
      - Richmond Bicentennial (Box 42, Folder 10)
      - Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad (Stations) (Box 42, Folder 11)
      - Roanoke Island (Lost Colony) (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence
      - Sachs, Mrs. Emanie N. - Satterfield, Jr., Dave E. - See Also Oversize Box 1, Folder 3 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Satterle, L.D. - Sayre, Margaret F. (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Scanlan, P.L. - Schwalm, J.A. (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Schwarz, Dorothy - Scrivenor, Arthur (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Sears, Julian D. - Seward, Mrs. Margaret (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - Shackelford, V.R. - Shepherd, Fred R. (Box 43, Folder 6)
      - Shepherd, Mrs. William A. - Shyke, I. (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - Sickel, H.S.J. - Skaggs, Nadine (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - Skinker, Bertha Rives - Smith, Mrs. Charles S. (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - Smith, Downing L. - Smith, Jane E. (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - Smith, Jess G. - Snider, Mrs. S.A. (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - Snidow, W.B. - Spender, Charles E. (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - Spencer, Mrs. James A. - Stauffer, W.T. (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Stear, Sue - Stevens, Mrs. Bessie (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Stevens, James L. - Story, W.J. (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - Stowell, Mrs. E.C. - Stultz, R.L. (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - Styron, Arthur - Swanson, Claude (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - Swanstrom, Mrs. Frederick E. - Sydnor, A.K. (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Additional Correspondence
      - Schwarzschild, William H. (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - Shield, Mrs. Conway H., Yorktown, VA (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Shurtleff, Dr. Harold R. (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Slemp, C. Bascom, Big Stone Gap, VA (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Sloan, Professor Harold S., NJ State Teachers College, Montclair, NJ (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - Smith, William (WPA Director) (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - Somerville, Thomas P., Gordonsville, VA (Box 46, Folder 6)
      - Spalding, Branch (Jackson's Movements of June 1862) (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - Spalding, Branch (Coordinating Superintendent, National Park Service, Fredericksburg) (part one) (Box 46, Folder 8)
      - Spalding, Branch (Coordinating Superintendent, National Park Service, Fredericksburg) (part two) (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - Squires, Dr. W.H.T. (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - Stern, Philip N. (CWA) (Architectural Survey) (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - Stevens, Dr. S.K. (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Stewart, Dr. T.D. (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Stewart, Victor W., Petersburg, VA (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Stone, Edward L., President, Stone Printing Company (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Topics
      - Sailor's Creek Battlefield Park (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Second Virginia Cavalry (Honor Roll) (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Seven Days Campaign, 1862 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Shenandoah National Park (Newspaper Clippings, etc.) - See Also Oversize Box 1, Folder 4 (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Shrines, Historic (Restorations) (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Simcoe's Military Journal (Box 47, Folder 10)
      - Society of Colonial Wars, Washington, DC (Box 47, Folder 11)
      - Society of War of 1812 (Essay) (Box 47, Folder 12)
      - Sons of Confederate Veterans (Dr. H.J. Eckenrode - Personal) (Box 47, Folder 13)
      - Southern Historical Society (Box 47, Folder 14)
      - Southwest Virginia Data (Box 47, Folder 15)
      - State Battlefield Parks (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - State Employees Credit Union (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - State Library (Richmond) (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - State Ownership of Property in Custody of a Society (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - State Parks (Virginia) (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - State Planning Board (Major Chars. J. Calrow, Consulting Director) - folder was empty
      - State Rights (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - State Safety Council (Box 48, Folder 7)
      - State Senate (Box 48, Folder 8)
      - Superintendents (Miscellaneous Superintendents) (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence
      - Tabb, T. Garnett - Taylor, Jaquelin P. (Box 48, Folder 10)
      - Taylor, John D. - Tewalt, John H. (Box 48, Folder 11)
      - Thalhimer, William B. - Thornton, Mrs. Ray (Box 48, Folder 12)
      - Tickner, Edith A. - Towle, H. Ledyard (Box 48, Folder 13)
      - Towles, Eleanor W. - Truxtun, I. Walke (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Tubbs, Eleanor - Turner, Mrs. W.R. (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - Turpin, Mrs. D.L. - Tyson, W.A. (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Additional Correspondence
      - Tapscott, K.A. (Assistant Landscape Architect) - See Also Oversize Box 1, Folder 5 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Terrell, Mrs. A.J., New Canton, VA (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - Truxtun, I. Walke (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - Tuck, William M. (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Tunnell, Mrs. Edith (Box 49, Folder 8)
      - Turner, Joseph A. (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Turner, W.R. (re: Hillsman House and Sailor's Creek Battlefield Park) (Box 49, Folder 10)
      - Tyler, Dr. Lyon G., Holdcroft, VA (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Topics
      - Taxation (Box 49, Folder 12)
      - Telegraph Road (Telegraph Line) (Box 49, Folder 13)
      - Thanksgiving (Box 49, Folder 14)
      - Town Marker Newspaper Clippings (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Travel Expenses (Revolving Fund), Bank Statements and Deposits, 1948-1950 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Trees (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Correspndence
      - Uhl, Raymond - Utterback, William I. (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Topics
      - Uniforms and Dress of the Army (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - United Daughters of the Confederacy (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - University of North Carolina Press (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - United States Army Officers who joined the Confederacy (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Unknown Folder (unsigned letters) (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence
      - Vail, Mrs. Agnes D. - Varney, Frank B. (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - Vasika, Joanne - Voorhis, Manning C. (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Additional Correspondence and Topics
      - Vavpetich, Rudolph (Box 50, Folder 12)
      - Vacation and Sick Leave Reports (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - Valley of Virginia (Date) (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Virginia Convention (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Virginia Electoral Table (1946) (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Virginia Personnel Act (1942) (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - Virginia Retirement System (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence
      - Everett Waddey Company - Wall, Mrs. E.E. (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Wall, J.B. - Walton, Jr., R.B. (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - War Price and Rationing Board - Waters, Vincent S. (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - Watkins, Mrs. Fannie Burton - Wayt, H.H. (Box 51, Folder 9)
      - Wealch, Mrs. Georgia W. - Wells, Vernoy R. (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Welsch, John B. - Whitaker, Mrs. A.E. (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Whitaker, Mrs. William - Whiting, Mrs. Pearl (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Whitley, Orlando - Wilbourn, Arthur E. (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Wilcher, T.S. - Williams, Eugene W. (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - Williams, Frances M. - Williams, Philip (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - Williams, Priscilla - Wiltshire, Byrd (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - Wiltshire, Jr., D.B. - Woldert, Albert (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - Wolf, Joseph C. - Wootten, Mrs. A. Guy (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - Word, A.C. - Wytheville Studios (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Additional Correspondence
      - Waller, General S. Gardner (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - Warner, T.H. (Box 53, Folder 6)
      - Wayland, Dr. John W., Harrisonburg, VA (Box 53, Folder 7)
      - Wertenbaker, Thomas Jefferson (Box 53, Folder 8)